Guide to the Stanford University, International Relations Program, Honors Theses SC4-6526 SC4-6526
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Theses, 1978-1998; Accession ARCH-2017-302
  - Brizius, Erin, Mythic Promise: Transitional Justice and the Protection of Human Rights in Sierra Leone, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Brosman, Greg, Protesting Jordan: The Role of Political Mobilization in the Liberalization Era, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Burkett, Chelsea, Tiger, Tiger: The Ideology of Childhood and the Use of Child Soldiers in Sri Lanka, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Chen, Tan Yan, Internet Censorship and Discourse: The Emergence of Public Opinion in China, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Hook, Marcia, Nations Within States: The Samaritans and National Identity in the Modern Middle East, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Kim, Gloria, Hearts for a Broken Homeland: Korean American Activism and the Politics of North Korean Human Rights, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Lam, Kaily, Venture Philanthropy: The Sustainability of a Hybrid Form, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Mela, Maham, Governance, Culture, and Economics: How They Matter for Educational Attainment, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Muzurovic, Admir, Media, Politics, and War: The Case of Yugoslavia from 1980 to 1991, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Nilson, Peter, The Payoff of Protectionism: The Effect of Industry-Specific Import Restrictions on U.S. Presidential Election Outcomes, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Rissman, Jeff, Man of the People: Vladimir Putin and Presidential Popularity in Post-Soviet Russia, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Scott, Chris, Koje-do: American POW Detention Policies during the Korean War, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Tellez, J.J., EnvironmentalPolitics in the Baja California Peninsula: Non-Government Organizations, Coalitions, and Campaigns, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Tio, Cathy, University Legal Aid in Beijing: Grassroots Realizations and Perceptions of Chinese Legam Reform, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Chang, Theodora, "Taking Care of our Own": Towards a Cross-Cultural Application of Long-Term Care for Chinese Elders, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Choi, Elaine, The Roles of United Nations Commissions of Inquiry in the Field of Human Rights, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Durand, Alessandra, Beyond the Gas Fields: Corporate Social Action in the Camisea Natural Gas Project, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Herbert, Tucker, Globalization on Hold: The Debate in Costa Rica, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Jones, Jennifer, More that 'Scraps of Paper': Treaty Durability Among Territorial Rivals, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Markman, Margaret, The Intersection of Political Economy and International Negotiations: An Investigation of French National Preferences for European integration, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Markuze, Stan, A Regional Analysis of Russia's Economic Growth, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Marsden, Lani Lee, The Consequences of China's Increasing Involvements in Africa: The Case of Angola from 1997-2006, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Munyon, Grant, Approaching catastrophe: An Analysis of Environmental Trends in Post-Revolution Iran, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Shakir, Omar, Taming the Pharaoh: Political Accountability in Modern Egypt, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Topacio Long, Jessica, No Social Demand, No State Supply: The Scope and Causes of the AIDS Crisis in Russia, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Walker, Ann, Kurdish Exceptionalism in Syria: A Comparative Study of Kurdish Resistance Movements in Iraq, Iran, Turkey, and Syria, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Anderson, Ashley, Bloodlines and Bombfields: An Empirical Analysis of Ethnic Terrorism in the Middle East and North Africa, 1980-2004, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Bashir, Aisha, Corruption and the Challenge of Institution Building in Nigeria: From the Evil Genius to the Anti-Corruption Czar, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Burk, Maura Lee, Microfinance and Women's Empowerment: Money Cannot Break Systemic Gender Biases: A Case Study of Intra-Household Resource Allocation in Gulu, Uganda, 2008 (Box 5)
  - arrington, Ryan, The Straw That Broke The Camel's Back: The Destabilizing Effects of Refugees on Host States, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Cramer, Marissa, Divisive Divas: How Female Pop-Stars in the Muslim World Embody Social Tension between Liberalism and Islamic Conservatism, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Green, Naima, Black and Bloody and Beautiful: Black Power in Australia, 1968-1972, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Hoy, Nick, Constitutional Autocracy: Popular Legitimation and Authoritarian Regression in Senegal and Madagascar, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Leifer, Kalani Kai, The Socialist Hangover: Democracy Satisfaction and Disparate Conceptions of the State in East and West Germany, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Narodick, Philip, An Assessment of the Private and Social Profitability of the Sugarcane Ethanol Industry, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Ragen, Patrick, "Special Relationships": Variations in China's Strategies Toward its Major African Trading Partners, 2008 (Box 6)
  - Roberts, Molly, The U.S.-China Trade Relationship: Explaining U.S. Antidumping Duties Duties on China, 2008 (Box 6)
  - Roubos, Katherine, Great Expectations: Effects of Anticipated Oil Rents in Uganda, 2008 (Box 6)
  - Bhojwani, Rashna, The Paradox of Slum Resettlement Policy: Explaining the Preferences of Relocated Slum Dwellers in Mumbai, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Bullock, Jennifer, Peace, Justice, and Accountability: Ugandan Perceptions their Implications for the International Criminal Court, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Cadet, Jennifer, Its own Worst Enemy: Turkey's Prolonged Attempts at Accession into European Union 1960-present, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Faller, Julie, The Hand that Gives: Ownership and Donorship in Developmental Aid, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Gibbs, Lucinda, Deepening Democracy Through Local Gevernment Reform: The Case of Participatory Budgeting in Brazil, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Groppi, Michele, Trade and the Israeli-Palestinian Conflict: A Weak Link, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Ilves, Luukas, Estonia's Revolution Toward Europe: The Transformation of Anti-Soviet Rebellion Into Post-Communist Governance Reforms, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Jackson, Aaron, Democratic Progress in Latin America: An Investigation of Indigenous Political Inclusion and Exclusion, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Montes- Delgado, Susana, The Case of Environmentally Displaced Persons or "Refugees" and the Role of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), 2009 (Box 6)
  - Oberman, Irina, The Great Democratic Divide: Explaining the Diverging Democratic Paths of Russia and Ukraine, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Ping, Whitney, What Matters Most and Why: Internet and External Factors for Democratization in Serbia 2000 and Comparison Case Studies, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Qayumi, Aaron, Incentivizing Reform: Selectivity, the Millennium Challenge Corperation, and a Case Study of Reform in El Salvador, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Saxten, Susie, Culteral Property Restitution: Case Study Analyses of Negotiations Between U.S. Art Museums and Source Nations, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Tanner, Quincy Jason, Draining the Southern Sea: Counterinsurgency Strategies of Mass Repression and Brutality in Thailand's Intractable Southern Conflict, 2009 (Box 6)
  - An, Vithia Chhean Ny, The Effects of Democratization on Foreign Direct Investment: A Time Series Analysis of Forms of Regime and FDI, 1970-1999, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Born, Natahsa, Evolving German Military Foreign Policy 1990-2010: Appeasing International Pressure in the Face of Domestic Divisions (Box 7)
  - Cryst, Elena, The Curse of the New Left: Ethnopopulism and Inequity in Bolivian Social Reform, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Flink, Mason, One of Them: The United States and the Murder of Six Jesuit Priests in El Salvador, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Forstein, Carolyn, A Slow Road to Justice: The Search for Rule of Law in Post-Soviet Russia, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Fuetsch, Elena,The Effects of Regional Economic Integration on Rural Development: Paraguay as a Case Study, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Glaser, Cady, Destined to Diverge: The Influence of Path Dependency on Post-Communist Political and Economic Trajectories, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Gregory, Julie, Mom and Pop in Modern China: The Political Economy of Urban Microbusiness, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Kapur, Ariel, Complicit in Atrocity: U.S. Involvement in the 1996 Invasion of the Democratic Republic of the Congo, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Kapur, Salone, Tweeting for Change: How Information Communication Technology (ICT) Driven Protest Movements are Creating Opportunities for Liberalization in Authoritarian Regimes, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Lawrence, Andrew, A Distraction in the Extractive Sector: The Shortcomings of the Extractive Industries Tranparency Initiative (EITI) in Azerbaijan, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Martin, Alyssa, Strange Bedfellops: Secularists, Feminists, and Hindu Nationalists on the Uniform Civil Code Debate in India, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Meredith, Alexis, Competition and Control: Corporate Social Responsibility in Sierra Leone's Mining Industry, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Monroe, Steve, Salafis in Parliament: Party Politics and Democratic Attitudes in the Gulf, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Ortega, Alejandro G., Disparate Democracies: A Comparative Analysis of Chile and Peru, 1973-2001, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Sangokoya, David Adeoluwa, Developing out of Displacement: Exploring Variation in Economic Recovery of Northern Uganda and Other Countries Following Displacement-Inducing Conflict, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Shakro, Peter, Answering the Call: The Joint Effects of Punitive Public Opinion and Institutional Responsiveness on Incarceration Rates in Contemporary Western Democracies, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Romero, Lara Sofia, Mapping the Paris-Metropole: Culteral Planning and Citizen Politics in an Age of Democratic Distrust, 2010 (Box 7)
  - Buhler, Eunice G. The Opportunity to Champion Religious Freedom: The Republic of Turkey, the Orthodox Christian Minority, and European Union Accession, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Chun, Annie- Marie, Lights, China, Action!: Why China's Film Industry Will Succeed Where France's Stagnated, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Cobert, Emma, Tailoring the Polish Tuxedo: An Analysis of Poland's Preparations for its Council of the European Union Presidency, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Gao, Shelley Xiao Yun, The China Menace: U.S. Preventative-War Thinking Towards the Emerging Chinese Nuclear Weapons Program in the 1960s, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Hoffman, Katherine, Autocratic Accountability?: The Political Economy of Health Care in Cuba, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Howard, Catherine, Hola, Negro!: A Comparative Exploration of the Intersectionality of Black Movements and Black Identity in Brazil, Colombia and Cuba, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Kulenovic, Ada, Chaos and Coordination in Multiparty Conflict Mediation: A Statistical Analysis and Case Studies of Single, Composite, and Team Mediation Efforts, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Wallerstein Dunaway, Alexei, Pursuing Accountability Through Civil Action: The Role of Transnational Advocacy Networks in Environmental Rights Litigation in Ecuador and the United States, 2011 (Box 7)
  - Alvarez, Joshua, The Grand Strategy of the Republic of Turkey, 2012 (Box 7)
  - Delgado, Christopher, From the Fiesta to the Debt Crisis: An Analysis of EU Cohesion Policy in Spain, 2012 (Box 7)
  - Hu, Olivia, The Brazilian Model: An Analysis of the Government's Role in Brazil's Ethanol Industry and Implications for Global Biofuel Markets, 2012 (Box 7)
  - McFadden, Christine, Why do Japanese Prime Ministers Visity Yasukuni Jinja Despite Adverse International Repercussions?, 2012 (Box 8)
  - Ou, Yin Yin, Marketing Charity: The Adoption of Branding Among South African HIV/AIDS Nonprofits, 2012 (Box 8)
  - Broner, Alexadra, Measuring Governance Reform in Post-Conflict States: A Comparative Case Study of Sierra Leone and Liberia, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Humphries, Arielle, I Used to Believe: Bosnian Women and the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Knudson Dekeyser, Elizabeth, National and Ethnic Identity in Africa, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Lewis, Hannah, How Knowing Mandarin Affects Trust in Chinese-Western Business Transactions, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Limoges, Jordan, Hearts in the Homeland: Investigating the roles of religious identity, policy, and discrimination in the integration of Yugoslavian immigrants in France, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Peddycoart, Michel, Outlasting Revolution: The Political Survival Strategies of Arab Constitutional Monarchies, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Rogers, Lilian, Chinese Muckrakers: Investigative Journalism, Censorship, and Reform, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Rosenberg, Rachel, Intra-Communal Religiouss Violence in Democratic Indigenous States, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Simmons, Carolyn, Globalization's Impact on National Education Expenditure: Analyzing Variation from 1970 to 2011 in Latin America and the Caribbean, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Doshay, Harris Winter, Serving the Son of Heaven: Explaining the Geographic Distribution of Bureaucrats in Early Modern China, 2014 (Box 8)
  - McFarlane, Amanda, The Rise of the Creole Language: An Evaluation of the Political Movement to Change Jamaica's Official Language to English and Jamaican Patois, 2014 (Box 8)
  - Papachristou, Nina, Keeping Our Pormises to the Persecuted: How the United States can Ensure Individual Justice for Asylum Seekers, 2014 (Box 8)
  - Thieme, Claudia Anne, Global Tax Practice in the Transition to a Digital Economy: Assessing Systematic Differences in Effective Corporate Tax Rates, 2014 (Box 8)
  - Zaldumbide, Andrea Sarahi, Cold War Covert Intervention in Latin America: Case Studies in U.S. Foreign Policymaking and the Dangers of Perception, 2014 (Box 9)
  - Donahoe, Megan, The Rhetoric of Suppression: Soviet Media Analysis of Eastern European Interventionism, 2015 (Box 9)
  - Parikh, Sanjana, Constitutional Promises and Environmental Protection: An Assessment of National Legal Rights to Nature, 2015 (Box 9)
  - Shump, Nicolas, Guest Worker Programs and Immigration, 2015 (Box 9)
  - Thakur, Natalya, Charity Work Abroad and the Unintended Democratic Deficit, 2015 (Box 9)
  - Weaser, Natasha, Evolution of the Sino-Saudi Relationship: Oil Partnership or Geopolitical Alliance?, 2015 (Box 9)
  - Mehra, Rebecca, Connecting the Drops: The Negotiation of the Indus Water Treaty, 2016 (Box 9)
  - Nelsen, Simone, Hosting: The Choice of Authoritarian States to Bid for the Olympic Games the Impact on Their Governments, 2016 (Box 9)
  - Sheils, Audrey, The Lines We Draw: Nationalism and the Border Creation at Sevres and Lausanne, 2016 (Box 9)
  - Cavallo, Christine, Dam Them All: On the Failure of Dams and Dam Building Frameworks, 2017 (Box 9)
  - Lee, Karen, Constitutional Engineering: Studying Promotions and Revocations of Religious Freedom in Thailand, 2017 (Box 9)
  - Whang, Yegina, Broken Nuclear Vows: Explaining why States Cheat on the Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty, 2017 (Box 9)
  - Willer, Kirsten, Citizenship Contestation and Reprisal Violence in sub-Saharan Africa, 2017 (Box 9)
  - Pfeister, Doug, The Promotion of Democracy and United States Policy toward Haiti, 1985-1992, 1993 May 20 (Box 9)
  - Peltz, Maxwell Costa Rica and the Reagan Administration: Sparring with a Giant, 1989 May 25 (Box 9)
  - Rodriguez, Dorena, The Reagan Doctrine and Pakistan, 1988 Spring (Box 9)
  - McGovern, John, Relations Between the United States and Nicaragua: The Carter Administration Precedent, 1987 May 28 (Box 9)
  - Torress, Kristin, Health Care or Wealth Care?: Mexican Health Care Reform in a Time of Economic and Political Liberalization, 2000, May 12 (Box 9)
  - Shapiro, Susanna, Movimento dos Trabalhadores Rurais Sem Terra (The Landless Workers Movement): Consolidating Brazil's Democracy Through the Struggle for Land, 1998 May 22 (Box 9)
  - Rubio, Martha, Human Rights and Political Transitions to Democracy in Latin America: Partial Truth and Little Justice, 1991 May 30 (Box 9)
  - Liu, Caitlin, The Role of Land Reform in the Postwar Economic Development of Taiwan, 1991 May 28 (Box 9)